legrand.us 2019-05-22

# Privacy | Legrand

#### **Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is important to Legrand North and Central America (hereinafter, the “Legrand”). This statement discloses the information practices for Legrand Web sites, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared. 

**Personal information**

In general, you can visit Legrand on the Internet without telling us who you are and without giving any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when we or our partners may need information from you. 

You may choose to give us personal information in a variety of situations. For example, you may want to give us information, such as your name and address or e-mail address, to correspond with you, to process an order  or to allow access to specific content. You may give us your credit card details to buy something from us or a description of your education and work experience in connection with a job opening at Legrand for which you wish to be considered. We intend to let you know how we will use such information before we collect it from you; if you tell us that you do not want us to use this information to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your requests, we will respect your wishes. If you give us personal information about somebody else, such as a spouse or work colleague, we will assume that you have their permission to do so. 

"Personal Information" for purposes of this Privacy Policy is the information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person, such as name, postal address (including billing and shipping addresses), telephone number, mobile number, email address, credit or debit card number, username, or profile picture.

We may receive Personal Information about you from third parties, such as social media services, commercially available sources, Legrand affiliates and business partners.  The Personal Information we receive from third parties may include your name, contact information, information about your transactions, purchase history, or relationships with various product and service providers, and your use of certain products. For example, if you access a Legrand Web Site through a social media service, the information we collect may also include your user ID and/or user name associated with that social media service, any information or content the social media service has the right to share with us, such as your profile picture, email address, friends list or information about the people and groups you are connected to and how you interact with them, and any information you have made public in connection with that social media service. The information we obtain depends on your privacy settings on the applicable social media service. When you access the Legrand Web site through social media services, you are authorizing Legrand to collect, store, and use such information and content in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

“Other Information" is any information that does not reveal your specific identity, such as browser information, mobile device ID, app usage data, information collected through cookies and other technologies, device characteristics, demographic information, geolocation data, and aggregated information.

We collect Other Information when you submit it to us.

**Using and Sharing Personal Information**

The following paragraphs describe in more detail how Legrand may use your personal information and with whom we may share it. Depending on the type of Legrand Web site you are visiting, one or more of the paragraphs may apply. 

**Fulfilling your transaction request**

If you request something from a Legrand Web site, for example, a product or service, a callback, or specific marketing materials, we will use the information you provide to fulfill your request. To help us do this, we may share information, with others, for instance, other parts of Legrand, Legrand’s resellers or distributors, financial institutions, shipping companies, postal or government authorities (for example, Customs authorities) involved in fulfilling your request. In connection with a transaction we may also contact you as part of our customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes. 

**Marketing Use**

The information you provide to Legrand on certain Legrand Web sites may also be used by Legrand and selected third parties for marketing purposes. Before we use it, however, we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether or not to have your information used in this way. To opt-out of receiving further marketing emails from Legrand, please follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each email. 

**Legrand Human Resources Web Sites, such as "Careers" on the Legrand home page**

In connection with a job application or inquiry, whether advertised on a Legrand Web site or otherwise, you may provide us with information about yourself, such as a resume or curriculum vitae. We may use this information throughout Legrand, and its related entities for the purpose of employment consideration or your inquiry. Except where you tell us not to, we will keep the information for future consideration. 

**Information for agents and/or distributors**

If you represent a Legrand agent and/or distributor, you may visit a Legrand Web site intended specifically for Legrand agents and/or distributors, or subscribe to an account on a non-public Web sites in the Agent Login. We may use information provided on any such site to administer and develop our business relationship with you, the agency or distributors you represent, and Legrand agents and/or distributors generally. For instance, this may involve using your information to send you details of Legrand agencies and/or distributor programs. It may also include sharing certain information with other agents and/or distributors (subject to any confidentiality obligations that may exist), or Legrand customers or prospects. In connection with a particular transaction or program, we may also contact you as part of customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes. 

**Use of Information in the Social Networking Environment**

Legrand may facilitate the use of social computing tools on some of its Web sites to enable online sharing and collaboration among members who have registered to use them. These include forums, wikis, blogs and other social media platforms. 

When registering to use these tools, you will be asked to provide certain personal information to Legrand. Depending on the platform, you may be agreeing to allow certain of the information you provide to be displayed as part of a public profile in the social networking environment in which you are registering to participate. Registration information which is not automatically made available to other participants as part any public profile will be subject to and protected in accordance with this privacy statement. 

Any other content you post, such as pictures, information, opinions, or any other type of personal information which you make available to other participants on these social platforms, is not subject to this privacy statement. Rather, such content is subject to the Terms of Use applicable to whichever forum, wiki, blog or other social media platform on which you are posting. Furthermore, additional guidelines and privacy policy information may be identified for your attention in regard of your use of such social media. Please make sure you review the Terms of Use and other policies applicable to any social media in which you elect to participate to better understand your, Legrand’s, and other parties' rights and obligations with regard to such content. In addition, you should be aware that the content you post on any such social computing platforms may be made broadly available to others inside and outside Legrand. 

**Use of Information To Protect The Rights Of Legrand And Others**  

We may use your Personal Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate in order to: protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of  Legrand, , our  affiliates or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements and our terms of use); protect the safety, privacy, and security of users of our products and services or members of the public; protect against fraud and other unlawful activity or for risk management purposes; comply with and enforce the law or legal process, including laws outside your country of residence, contractual obligations, and our policies; or respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence.

**Other Legrand Web Site Notices**

In some cases, specific Legrand Web sites may contain other notices about their use and the information practices applicable to those sites. 

**Information Security and Quality**

We intend to protect your personal information and to maintain its quality. We implement appropriate measures and processes, such as using encryption when transmitting certain sensitive information, to help us to keep your information secure and to maintain its quality during transmission. We make reasonable efforts to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk of the processing, taking into account the costs of implementation and nature of the processing of Personal Information. However, no one can guarantee the complete safety of your information. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting the Legrand Web site coordinator in accordance with the instructions below.

We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

**Supplementing Information**

From time to time we may supplement information you give us via a Legrand Web site with information from other sources, such as information validating your address or other available information about businesses. This is to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect and to help us provide a better service. 

**Use of Suppliers**

In some cases Legrand uses suppliers to collect, use, analyze and otherwise process information on its behalf. It is Legrand’s practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with Legrand’s policies. 

**Mergers and Acquisitions**

Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons,  Legrand  decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Legrand's practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions. 

**Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Technologies**

We sometimes collect non-identifiable information from visits to our Web sites to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit, and we also measure visitor activity on Legrand Web sites, but we do so in ways that keep the information non-identifiable. Legrand or others on Legrand’s behalf may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service. 

Also, when we collect personal data from you in a transaction, we may extract some information about that transaction in a non-identifiable format and combine it with other non-identifiable information such as clickstream data. This information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns. This information is not stored or reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner you can disable your cookies. 

We collect the information we mentioned in the previous paragraphs through the use of various technologies, including one called "cookies". A cookie is a piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as an anonymous tag that identifies your computer but not you. Some Legrand pages use cookies, sent by Legrand or its third party vendors, or other technologies to better serve you when you return to the Web site. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, some Web sites may not work properly. 

Some Legrand Web sites also use Web beacon or other technologies to better tailor those sites to provide better customer service. These technologies may be in use on a number of pages across Legrand’s Web sites. When a visitor accesses these pages, a non-identifiable notice of that visit is generated which may be processed by us or by our suppliers. These Web beacons usually work in conjunction with cookies. If you don't want your cookie information to be associated with your visits to these pages, you can set your browser to turn off cookies.. 

In some circumstances, we may work with third parties to provide services on our site.  For example, we use analytics services supported by third party companies who generate analytics cookies on our behalf.  We may not have access to these cookies, although we may use statistical information arising from the cookies provided by these third parties to customize content and for the other purposes described above.  These companies may also transfer this information to other parties where required to do so by law, or where such other parties process the information on their behalf. We may not control these third-party cookies and their use may be governed by the privacy policies of the third parties employing these cookies. They may, however, use persistent identifiers to anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these sites. This Policy does not apply to and we are not responsible for such persistent identifiers used by these analytics and advertising companies.

To learn about these cookies and to disable or reject third-party cookies, please refer to the relevant third party’s website.

You may refuse to accept cookies from the Legrand  Web Site at any time by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse cookies. Further information about the procedure to follow in order to disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website via your help screen. You may wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html> for information on commonly used browsers. Please note that by disabling or blocking any or all cookies, some features of the Legrand  Web Site may not operate as intended, or you may not have access to features or personalization available through the Legrand  Web Site. Analytics cookies can also be managed via the following links:

  * <https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

**Do Not Track**

Some browsers or other tools include “Do Not Track”  features which, when turned on, send a signal to websites you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked across websites over time. However, since no technology standard for Do Not Track signals has been developed or adopted to date, Legrand does not currently respond to Do Not Track signals.  Legrand  will follow the progress of the W3C in developing the standard.

Personal Information of Children under the age of 16

We do not intentionally gather personal information from visitors who are under the age of 16.  If a child under 16 submits personal information to the site and we learn that the personal information is the information of a child under 16, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible.  If you believe that we might have any personal information from a child under 16, please contact us at: at [**marketing.group@legrand.us**](mailto:marketing.group@legrand.us)

**Service Quality Monitoring**

Certain Web transactions may also involve you calling us or our calling you. Please be aware that it is Legrand’s general practice to monitor and in some cases record such calls for staff training or quality assurance purposes. 

**Disclosures Required By Law**

Please be aware that in certain circumstances, it is possible that personal information may be subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders. 

**Links to non-Legrand Web sites**

Legrand Web sites may contain links to other Web sites. Legrand is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other Web sites. 

**California Privacy Rights**

California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing use. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2018 will receive information regarding 2017 sharing activities).  To make such a request, please contact us at [marketing.group@legrand.us](mailto:marketing.group@legrand.us). **** You can also contact us at: 

Legrand North America   
60 Woodlawn Street  
West Hartford, CT 06110  
Attention: Webmaster

**Notification of Changes**

This privacy statement was last updated on October 1, 2018. A notice will be posted on our Web site home page for 30 days whenever this privacy statement is changed in a material way. 

**Privacy Questions and Access**

If you have a question about this statement or Legrand’s handling of your information, you can send an email to the Legrand Web site coordinator. The address for this is  [marketing.group@legrand.us](mailto:marketing.group@legrand.us). You can also contact us at: 

Legrand North America   
60 Woodlawn Street  
West Hartford, CT 06110  
Attention: Webmaster

We ask that you not disclose any sensitive Personal Information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) when contacting us.

If you wish to obtain a copy of particular information you provided to  Legrand or if you become aware the information is incorrect and you would like us to correct it contact us at [marketing.group@legrand.us](mailto:marketing.group@legrand.us).

Before Legrand is able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, however, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details to help us to respond to your request. We will contact you within 30 days your request. 

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Information provided until after the completion of such transaction  or promotion).

This Web site is maintained by Legrand North and Central America.
